Guide to the David C. Jung Papers, 1968-1983
Department of Special Collections
Jung, David C. Papers,
1968-1983
M0844
Jung, David C.
8 linear ft. (102 items).
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Market reports, investment evaluations, management studies, etc. made by Quantum Science Corporation. 16 mm sound film, I.M. CLONE, which describes a day in the life of a business executive in the year 2000.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
Gift of David C. Jung, 1986, 1987, and 1988.
Biography
David C. Jung served as Staff Vice President, ISG Market Development for the McDonnell Douglas Information Systems Group.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Market reports, investment evaluations, management studies, etc. made by Quantum Science Corporation. 16 mm sound film, I.M. CLONE, which describes a day in the life of a business executive in the year 2000.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Jung, David C.; Amdahl Computer Corporation.; Ball Corporation.; Dirks Electronic Corporation.; International Business Machines Corporation.; McDonnell Douglas Automation Company.; Memorex Corporation.; Quantum Science Corporation.; Computer engineering.; Microelectronics industry--California--Santa Clara County.
Collection Contents
- Quantum Science. Minicoputers and Microcomputers (The Squeeze is on) 1974, 1 volume: 226 pps. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Very important early study detailing what impact micros would have on minis and Silicon Valley firms.
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK - Computer Services Forecast Part I1969, 1 volume: 110 pps. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Purchased by 30 leading computer firms to support market and product decisions (IBM, Burroughs, etc.). Describes impact on Silicon Valley firms.
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK - Computer Services (Domestic) Forecast Part II1969, 1 volume: 110 pps. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK - Computer Services (Domestic) Forecast Part III1969, 1 volume: 69 pps. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK - Computer Services Strategy Program, Vol. I. Management Action Report1973, 1 volume: 54 pps. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK Report - Computer Services Strategy Program (Vol. II) Strategies1973, 1 volume: 487 pps. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK Report - Computer Services Program / 73 Vol. III / Data Base1973, 1 volume: 249 pps. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK Strategy Report - Management Action in Technology - Computer Equipment Strategy Program1974, 1 volume: 90 pps. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK Computing Equipment Strategy Program 1974-1979, Vol. III / Data Base1974, 1 volume: 402 pps. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK - Strategy for Entering Time-Sharing, Part I1970, 1 volume: 100 pps. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  The pioneering study for this now industry. Discusses Silicon Valley Ffrms.
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK - Strategy for Entering Time-Sharing, Part II1970, 1 volume: 50 pps. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK - Logicon 2x21970, 1 volume: 128 pps. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Study helped NYSE firm to decide whether to get into the computer business.
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK Computer Equipment Strategy Program, Vol. I Management Action Report1973, 1 volume: 130 pps. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Purchased by 35 leading computer firms to help plan equipment and technology directions. Discusses Silicon Valley firms.
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK Network Information Services, Part I1968, 1 volume: 90 pps. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK Network Information Services, Part II1968, 1 volume: 90 pps. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK Associate Program Equipment Forecast1972, 1 volume: 646 pps. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK Associate Program Equipment Forecast (Final Report)1972, 1 volume: 294 pps. (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK Computer Equipment Study1970, 1 volume: 180 pps. (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Quantum Science. MAPTEK Strategy Study Computer Services market, Winter 1970 - 19711971, 1 volume: 200 pps. (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Quantum Science. AMDAHL1972 Aug. 7, 1 volume: 141 pps. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  The fundamental study of AMDAHL which resulted in the Japanese making a major investment.
- Quantum Science. AMDAHL1974, 1 volume: 278 pps. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  Used by Japanese to justify entering into the U.S. semiconductor market. Discusses Silicon Valley firms.
- Quantum Science. IBM SB Computer1974, 1 volume: 114 pps. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  Market review of IBM's early small business computer program.
- Quantum Science. Dirk's Investment Analysis1972, 1 volume: 69 pps. (Box 4, Folder 23)
  Study performed of Dirks computer to support venture corporate investment by Hale. A Silicon Valley firm.
- Quantum Science. McAuto TSO1974, 1 volume: 95 pps. (Box 4, Folder 24)
  Study of McAuto's Time-Sharing Services.
- Quantum Science. Computer Services Major Groupings of Competitors1974, 1 volume: 130 pps. (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Quantum Science. Remote Computing Industry1974, 1 volume: 130 pps. (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Quantum Science. Vol. Three-Data Base MAPTEK Computer Services Strategy Progrm 1974-1979 Management Action Report1974, 1 volume: 412 pps. (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Quantum Science. Vol. Three-Data Base MAPTEK Computer Services Strategy Progrm 1974-1979 Management Action Report1974, 1 volume: 412 pps. (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Quantum Science. A Samson Report - Video Casette1971, Video casette: 110 minutes (Box 4, Folder 28)
  Early review of technologies and market/technology format.
- Quantum Science. Quantum - Industry Report - The Intelligent Factory1974, 1 volume: 182 pps. (Box 4, Folder 29)
  Important early study of computer-aided manufacturing products and market needs.
- Quantum Science. Automated Information Storage and Retrieval1973, 1 volume: 132 pps. (Box 4, Folder 31)
  Discusses Silicon Valley firms.
- Quantum Science. Ball Corp. OCR/OMR Technologies1974, 1 volume: 39 pps. (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Quantum Science. Mass Storage Custom Study1973, 1 volume: 30 pps. (Box 5, Folder 33)
  Done for Control Data. Evaluates several Silicon Valley firms.
- Quantum Science. SABER Management System Evaluation1974, 1 volume: 158 pps. (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Quantum Science. Computer Industry Trends Vol. I1971, 1 volume: 120 pps. (Box 5, Folder 35)
  Japan Electronic Industry Development Association
- Quantum Science. JIPDEC Industry Trends Vol. II1971, 1 volume: 200 pps. (Box 5, Folder 36)
  Helped Japanese invest in Silicon Valley.
- Quantum Science. Network Information Services Strategy Session1970, 1 volume: 20 pps. (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Quantum Science. Network Information Service, 1974-19801974-1980, 1 volume: 48 pps. (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Quantum Science. Remote Computing Directory 1974, 1 volume: 275 pps. (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Quantum Science. The $500 Million Computer Services Vendor1974, 1 volume: 81 pps. (Box 6, Folder 40)
  Majority study done for Martin Marietta Corporation.
- Quantum Science. Summary Report U.S. Computer Services Industry1974, 1 volume: 294 pps. (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Quantum Science. Automated Business Services Market Phase I Report1973, 1 volume: 151 pps. (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Quantum Science. Evaluation of Memorex1974, 1 volume: 96 pps. (Box 6, Folder 43)
  Done for Bank of America. Review of tape and DISC technology. Analysis of competitors.
- Quantum Science. Magnetic Bubble Memories, Vol. I, Preliminary Report1972, 1 volume: 80 pps. (Box 6, Folder 44)
  High technology product study. Covered many Silicon Valley firms.
- Quantum Science. Office Automation, Vol. I, Management Action Report1972, 1 volume: 88 pps. (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Quantum Science. Facilities Management (2)1971, 1 volume: 57 pps. (Box 6, Folder 46)
  Market Study. Reviewed several Silicon Valley competitors.
- Quantum Science. Remote Computing Markets Network Information Services, Vol. I1971, 1 volume: 110 pps. (Box 7, Folder 47)
- Quantum Science. Remote Computing Markets Network Information Services, Vol. II1971, 1 volume: 225 pps. (Box 7, Folder 48)
- Quantum Science. Remote Computing Markets Data Base III (Network Information Services)1971, 1 volume: 150 pps. (Box 7, Folder 49)
- Quantum Science. Remote Computing Markets Federal Information Systems Presentation1971, 1 volume: 100 pps. (Box 7, Folder 50)
- Quantum Science. Leading Edge Survey, Vol. I1969, 1 volume: 130 pps. (Box 7, Folder 51)
  Major study done for IBM of their 30 largest customers.
- Quantum Science. Leading Edge Survey, Vol. II1969, 1 volume: 130 pps. (Box 7, Folder 52)
- Quantum Science. Leading Edge Survey, Vols. III and IV1969, 1 volume: 130 pps. (Box 8, Folder 53)
- Quantum Science. Analysis of New Product Opportunities Task II1972, 1 volume: 200 pps. (Box 8, Folder 54)
- Quantum Science. Services Opportunities for SORBUS Task II1972, 1 volume: 90 pps. (Box 8, Folder 55)
- Quantum Science. Data Entry1972, 1 volume: 118 pps. (Box 8, Folder 56)
- Quantum Science. CPA Market Analysis1974, 1 volume: 131 pps. (Box 8, Folder 57)
  Provides product ideas for Silicon Valley firms.
- Quantum Science. The Electronics Business Products1972, 1 volume: 89 pps. (Box 8, Folder 58)
- Quantum Science. LOGICON Long-Range Plan1972, 1 volume: 152 pps. (Box 8, Folder 59)
  Review of commercial opportunities for several aerospace and defense technologies.
- Quantum Science. Machine Tool Controller Markets Analysis1972, 1 volume: 118 pps. (Box 9, Folder 60)
  Done for Excello Corp.
- Quantum Science. Study on MAS-Based Networks Information Services1974, 1 volume: 141 pps. (Box 9, Folder 61)
- Quantum Science. Computer Memory Markets and Technology-Management Action1971, 1 volume: 73 pps. (Box 9, Folder 62)
  Very important semi-conductor memory study. Evaluates almost all Silicon Valley chip manufacturers.
- Quantum Science. EDP Security Requirements Analysis1972, 1 volume: 330 pps. (Box 9, Folder 63)
  Done for Janpanese trade association.
- Quantum Science. Computer Services Strategy Program (Final Report)1972, 1 volume: 330 pps. (Box 9, Folder 64)
- Quantum Science. Remote Computing Markets Dedicated Information Systems Management Action Summary1970, 1 volume: 49 pps. (Box 9, Folder 65)
  Key study of large corporation's future use of EDP. Results, discuss implications for Silicon Valley firms.
- Quantum Science. Remote Computing Markets Dedicated Information Systems Management Action Summary, Vol. I1970, 1 volume: 146 pps. (Box 10, Folder 66)
- Quantum Science. Remote Computing Markets Dedicated Information Systems Management Action Summary, Vol. II1970, 1 volume: 284 pps. (Box 10, Folder 67)
- Quantum Science. Computer Services Strategy Program Presentation1973, 1 volume: 105 pps. (Box 10, Folder 68)
- Quantum Science. Small Business Data Processing Opportunities, Vol. I, Strategies Outlook1973, 1 volume: 295 pps. (Box 10, Folder 69)
  Major early study of the use of mini and micro computers in small business markets. Evaluates many Silicon Valley firms.
- Quantum Science. Small Business Data Processing Opportunities, Vol. II, Part A, Industry Analysis1973, 1 volume: 282 pps. (Box 10, Folder 70)
- Quantum Science. Small Business Data Processing Opportunities, Vol. II, Part B, Industry Analysis1973, 1 volume: 262 pps. (Box 11, Folder 71)
- Quantum Science. Network Information Services, 1974-1980, Vol. IV1974-1980, 1 volume: 134 pps. (Box 11, Folder 72)
- Morgan Stanley. Computer Sharing Services, Inc.1983, 1 volume: 300 pps. (Box 11, Folder 73)
  A company evaluation.
- All American Engineering VTR1968, 1 volume: 200 pps. (Box 11, Folder 74)
  A technology study of various video tape recorders. Market forecast of tape usage (Memorex).
- Corporate. Long-Term Impact of ADR Acquisition on Tymshare1980, 1 volume: 70 pps. (Box 11, Folder 75)
  A Silicon Valley company.
- Acquisition of TeleCheck Services, Inc. (TSI) - Update1980, 1 volume: 50 pps. (Box 11, Folder 76)
- INPUT. Computer Services Industry. 1978 Annual Report.1978, 1 volume: 318 pps. (Box 12, Folder 77)
- INPUT. Market Analysis Service-Annual Presentation 1978 Computer Service Industry1978, 1 volume: 129 pps. (Box 12, Folder 78)
- INPUT. Investment Opportunities in the Computer Services Industry1977, 1 volume: 184 pps. (Box 12, Folder 79)
- INPUT. Acquisition Strategies for Computer Services Companies Impact Report #21979, 1 volume: 131 pps. (Box 12, Folder 80)
- INPUT. ADAPSO Annual Computer Services Industry Report1979, 1 volume: 104 pps. (Box 12, Folder 81)
- MARCOM, Inc. A Study of the Communications and Telemetry Equipment Markets1968, 1 volume: 129 pps. (Box 12, Folder 82)
- MARCOM, Inc. CELENESE Markets 1969, 1 volume: 159 pps. (Box 13, Folder 83)
  Discusses several Silicon Valley firms.
- MARCOM, Inc. RCA - Transportation Industry1968, 1 volume: 145 pps. (Box 13, Folder 84)
  Discusses market opportunities for electronic products in transportation.
- Tymshare, Inc. Personnel Policy and Practice1978, 1 volume: 50 pps. (Box 13, Folder 85)
  A Silicon Valley firm.
- Quantum Science. Financial OCR/OMR1974, 1 volume: 39 pps. (Box 13, Folder 86)
- Tymshare, Inc. Option Shared ATM Network1974, Brochure: 12 pps. (Box 13, Folder 87)
  Early EFT System.
- American Management Association. Center for Management Development1978, 1 volume: 200 pps. (Box 13, Folder 88)
- SBS Publishing. Banking EDP Product and Services Opportunities - The Reality Aheat for EFT1978, 1 volume: 140 pps. (Box 13, Folder 89)
  Refers to several Silicon Valley firms.
- ADAPSO. Industry Survey1974, 1 volume: 50 pps. (Box 14, Folder 90)
  Covers Computer Service industry and many Silicon Valley firms.
- Small Business Systems. High Value-Added Product Strategies-Potential and Pitfalls1977, 1 volume: 140 pps. (Box 14, Folder 91)
  Report aimed at Silicon Valley high technology firms.
- Conversion Management Systems, Inc. Business Plan1980, 1 volume: 180 pps. (Box 14, Folder 92)
- Frost & Sullivan, Inc. Financial Services and Associated Financial Terminals in Retail Environment #A7061979, 1 volume: 297 pps. (Box 14, Folder 93)
- ARISTADATA. Executive Strategic Planning Service. Computer Service Industry 1979 Forecast1979, 1 volume: 308 pps. (Box 14, Folder 94)
- Weeks Research Associates. Microband Pay Television - Analysis and Ten-Year Forecast1980, 1 volume: 133 pps. (Box 15, Folder 95)
- C-E-I-R, Inc. The Data Utility, 1 volume: 68 pps. (Box 15, Folder 96)
- Optimum Systems, Inc. Computing Services-Alternatives to In-House Systems, 1 volume: 100 pps. (Box 15, Folder 97)
- Tymshare, Inc. Financial Policies and Procedures1983, 1 volume: 200 pps. (Box 15, Folder 98)
- J.L. Kellogg Graduate School of Management, Northwestern University. Executive Programs, James L. Allen Center1983, 1 volume: 300 pps. (Box 15, Folder 99)
- Browne, Bortz and Coddington. TTN Revenue and Expenditure Model: Three Service Options1981 Mar., 1 volume: 200 pps. (Box 15, Folder 100)
- R.A. Larsen. Financial Systems for CPA Firms and Accounting Firms1975 Jan., 1 volume: 100 pps. (Box 15, Folder 101)
- McKinsey & Co., Inc. Three Yards and a Cloud of Dust Tymshare, Inc. 1980 Nov. 3, 1 volume: 103 pps. (Box 15, Folder 102)